David Locke Papers MS122
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Dagomba Dance Drumming materials, 1989 -- 2010; MS122.002; 788 Digital Object(s)
  - Nagbiegu, solo dance, 2001 -- 2010; MS122.002.009; 35 Digital Object(s)
    Nagbiegu is the appellation for Naa Abudu. A Dagomba chief, Naa Tutuari, had taken Chemba land, and the present Chemba chief, Kofi, threatened Abudu that he would take the land back. Naa Abudu replied that he is a nagbiegu, a bad cow, by which he meant that he would come and take what he wanted from them and the rest would be spoiled. The drum language for Nagbiegu lists the bad things that will happen to someone who challenges Naa Abudu.
    - Story of Nagbiegu, appellation of Naa Abudu, 2001; MS122.002.009.00001; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
      Told by Abubakari Lunna on March 2 and 6, 2001. Edited by David Locke. Describes the origins of the Nagbiegu rhythm, which is played for the chief Naa Abudu.
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.009.00002; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.009.00003; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.009.00004; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.009.00005; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.009.00006; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.009.00007; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.009.00008; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.009.00009; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.009.00010; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.009.00011; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.009.00012; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.009.00013; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.009.00014; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.009.00015; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.009.00016; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.009.00017; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.009.00018; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Nagbiegu drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.009.00019; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drumming transcription, 2010; MS122.002.009.00020; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead gung-gong drumming transcription, 2010; MS122.002.009.00021; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language audio (1) Doo bi nye o to dapala, 2010; MS122.002.009.00022; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language audio (2) signal to nagbiegu gnuni daa ku o, 2010; MS122.002.009.00023; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language audio (3) che guru kum o che guru, 2010; MS122.002.009.00024; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language audio (4) che guru to gbam o che guru, 2010; MS122.002.009.00025; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language audio (5) che guru che guru che guru gbam o, 2010; MS122.002.009.00026; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language audio (6) che guru che guru che guru kum o, 2010; MS122.002.009.00027; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language audio (7) che guru che guru che guru to kum o, 2010; MS122.002.009.00028; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language audio (8a) yelmangli dangzhiya zhiri zan labira, 2010; MS122.002.009.00029; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language audio (8b) yelmangli dangzhiya zhiri zan labira, 2010; MS122.002.009.00030; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language audio (9a) bangnarigu din luri ngmanga, 2010; MS122.002.009.00031; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language audio (9b) bangnargu din luri ngmanga, 2010; MS122.002.009.00032; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu lead lunga drum language audio (10) tung gnmari din luri salima, 2010; MS122.002.009.00033; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu answer lunga drum language audio (1) nagbiegu la to to to, 2010; MS122.002.009.00034; Locke, David
    - Nagbiegu answer lunga drum language audio (2) nyo o, 2010; MS122.002.009.00035; Locke, David
  - Naani Goo, solo dance, 2001 -- 2010; MS122.002.010; 30 Digital Object(s)
    Naani Goo is the appellation of Naa Andani. There was a tribe called the Chemba who were expected to pay a tax to the Dagombas. When Naa Abudu sent someone to collect the tax, the Chemba sent for help from the Zambarima tribe of Mali to fight against the Dagombas. Naa Abudu called his brother, Naa Andani, to help with the fight. When Naa Andani tried to round up the rest of his family, they refused and told Andani that Abudu was trying to get him killed so that he could make his own son chief. The drum language is a warning about not being able to trust others, and it stems from the brothers' refusal to help Andani.
    - Story of Naani Goo, appellation of Naa Andani, 2001; MS122.002.010.00001; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
      Told by Abubakari Lunna on March 2 and 6, 2001. Edited by David Locke. Describes the origins of the Naani Goo rhythm that tells the story of how Naa Andani became chief.
    - Naani Goo lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.010.00002; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.010.00003; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.010.00004; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.010.00005; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.010.00006; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.010.00007; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.010.00008; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.010.00009; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.010.00010; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.010.00011; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.010.00012; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.010.00013; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.010.00014; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.010.00015; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.010.00016; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.010.00017; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.010.00018; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Naani Goo drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.010.00019; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drum language audio (1) salaga limam, ku pagi o to, 2010; MS122.002.010.00020; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drum language audio (2) goo beri pam, 2010; MS122.002.010.00021; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drum language audio (3) gohi beri pam, 2010; MS122.002.010.00022; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drum language audio (4) gohi beri pam goo beri pam, 2010; MS122.002.010.00023; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drum language audio (5) mira mira goo beri pam, 2010; MS122.002.010.00024; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drum language audio (6) mira mira naani goo, 2010; MS122.002.010.00025; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drum language audio (7) to to goo beri pam, 2010; MS122.002.010.00026; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drum language audio (8) to to naani goo, 2010; MS122.002.010.00027; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drum language audio (9) mira mira to gohi beri pam, 2010; MS122.002.010.00028; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo lead lunga drum language audio (10) to gohi beri, 2010; MS122.002.010.00029; Locke, David
    - Naani Goo answer lunga drum language audio (1) To zom Naani Goo la, 2010; MS122.002.010.00030; Locke, David
  - Zim Taai Kulga, solo dance, 2001 -- 2010; MS122.002.011; 25 Digital Object(s)
    Zim Tai Kulga is one of the appellations for Naa Alaasani. Before he was given a title, Alaasani behaved like a drunkard so that others wouldn't see him as a threat for the chieftancy. Under that pretense, he was made chief of Karaga, a position from which he could eventually ascend to Yaa-naa.
    - Story of Zim Taai Kulga, appellation of Naa Alaasani, 2001; MS122.002.011.00001; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
      Told by Abubakari Lunna on March 2 and 6, 2001. Edited by David Locke. Describes the origins of the Zim Taai Kulga rhythm that tells the story of how Naa Alaasani became chief.
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.011.00002; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.011.00003; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.011.00004; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.011.00005; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.011.00006; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.011.00007; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.011.00008; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.011.00009; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.011.00010; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.011.00011; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.011.00012; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.011.00013; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.011.00014; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.011.00015; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.011.00016; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.011.00017; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.011.00018; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Zim Taai Kulga drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.011.00019; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead lunga drum language audio (1) Abulai dapal', Alaasani, 2010; MS122.002.011.00020; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead lunga drum language audio (1) nyema nyema zim pali kulga ni, 2010; MS122.002.011.00021; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead lunga drum language audio (2) tipariga tipariga Alaasani, 2010; MS122.002.011.00022; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga lead lunga drum language audio (3) katini dapal' tipariga, 2010; MS122.002.011.00023; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga answer lunga drum language audio (1) palnim' wolim je, 2010; MS122.002.011.00024; Locke, David
    - Zim Taai Kulga answer lunga drum language audio (2) kulpalnim wolim jeVar, 2010; MS122.002.011.00025; Locke, David
  - Tampima Dundong, solo dance, 1999 -- 2010; MS122.002.012; 24 Digital Object(s)
    Tampima Dundon is the appellation for Naa Alaasani. When Naa Andani died, the kingmakers convened and chose Naa Alaasani. The regent at the time disagreed with this decision, and wanted a different man to be Yaa-naa. This led to a stalemate that lasted several years. One of Naa Alaasani's relatives, Kor-naa Bukali, enlisted the help of the British to kill the regent to make way for Alaasani to become Yaa-naa. The words of the song talk about having a house made of strong stone, by which Alaasani means that he is strong because of his family.
    - Story of Tampima Dundon, appellation of Naa Alaasani, 1999; MS122.002.012.00001; Locke, David; Lunna, Abubakari
      Told by Abubakari Lunna on March 1, 1999. Edited by David Locke. This story describes the origins of the Tampima rhythm, which is played in celebration of the chief Naa Alaasani.
    - Tampima Dundong lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.012.00002; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.012.00003; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.012.00004; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.012.00005; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.012.00006; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.012.00007; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.012.00008; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.012.00009; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.012.00010; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.012.00011; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.012.00012; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.012.00013; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong lead gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.012.00014; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.012.00015; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong lead gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.012.00016; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.012.00017; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.012.00018; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Tampima Dundong drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.012.00019; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Tampima Dundong lead lunga drum language audio (1) Abulai dapala Alaasani, 2010; MS122.002.012.00020; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong lead lunga drum language audio (2) zim pali kulga, 2010; MS122.002.012.00021; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong lead lunga drum language audio (3) ansarisi maadi kpimba vuya karimbaadana, 2010; MS122.002.012.00022; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong lead lunga drum language audio (4) tipariga tipariga Naawuni kulsi, 2010; MS122.002.012.00023; Locke, David
    - Tampima Dundong answer lunga drum language audio (1), 2010; MS122.002.012.00024; Locke, David
  - Zambalantong, solo dance, 1993 -- 2010; MS122.002.013; 25 Digital Object(s)
    Zambalanton is the appellation of Kar-baa Bukali. When Bukali was young, he was warned that someone might try to hurt him. Later, he was given a royal smock by a chief as a gift, but he never wore it because suspected that it might be dangerous. One day, that chief's son visited Bukali, and as a test he gave the smock back to the chief's son to wear. The son died soon after donning the smock. The drum language of Zambalanton talks about someone trying to set a trap and catching themselves rather than their intended target.
    - Story of Zambalantong, appellation of Kar-naa Bukali, 1993; MS122.002.013.00001; Locke, David; Lunna, Abubakari
      Told by Abubakari Lunna on June 9, 1993. Edited by David Locke. Describes the Zambalanton rhythm played in celebration of the chief Kar-naa Bukali.
    - Zambalantong lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.013.00002; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.013.00003; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.013.00004; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.013.00005; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.013.00006; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.013.00007; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.013.00008; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.013.00009
    - Zambalantong answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.013.00010; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.013.00011; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.013.00012; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.013.00013; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.013.00014; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.013.00015; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.013.00016; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.013.00017; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.013.00018; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Zambalantong drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.013.00019; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Zambalantong lead lunga drum language audio (1) Gbungbiri leli dapal', 2010; MS122.002.013.00020; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead lunga drum language audio (2a) nuni bari gbago o bia, 2010; MS122.002.013.00021; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead lunga drum language audio (2b) nuni bari gbago o bia, 2010; MS122.002.013.00022; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead lunga drum language audio (2c) nuni bari gbago o bia, 2010; MS122.002.013.00023; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong lead lunga drum language audio (3) gbungbiri leli m-bala la, 2010; MS122.002.013.00024; Locke, David
    - Zambalantong answer lunga drum language audio (1) bari gbago o bia, 2010; MS122.002.013.00025; Locke, David
  - Dambobugo, solo dance, 1993 -- 2010; MS122.002.014; 24 Digital Object(s)
    Dambobugo is the appellation of Savelugu-naa Bukali Kantamparam. When Bukali was chief of Kpatenga, the previous chief of Savelugu and many people in the town tried in vain to prevent him from being promoted to that higher post. After he had gain the chieftaincy of Savelugu, the weather was particularly good for farming and the harvest was plentiful. The drum language for Dambobugo says he has defeated his enemies but continues to think good of everyone. God has rewarded his generous spirit by bringing rain so that big families can eat well and be satisfied.
    - Story of Dambobugo, appellation of Saveluga-naa Bukali Kantamparum, 1993; MS122.002.014.00001; Locke, David; Lunna, Abubakari
      Told by Abubakari Lunna on June 23, 1993. Edited by David Locke. Describes the Dambobogu rhythm played in celebration of Savelugu-naa Bukali Kantamparum.
    - Dambobugo lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.014.00002; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.014.00003; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.014.00004; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.014.00005; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.014.00006; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.014.00007; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.014.00008; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.014.00009; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.014.00010; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.014.00011; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.014.00012; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.014.00013; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo lead gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.014.00014; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.014.00015; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo lead gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.014.00016; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.014.00017; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.014.00018; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Dambobugo drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.014.00019; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Dambobugo lead lunga drum language audio (1) nin yi ngo baga ni namo dapala, 2010; MS122.002.014.00020; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo lead lunga drum language audio (2) konkushema sigri kulga konsi zori balibali, 2010; MS122.002.014.00021; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo lead lunga drum language audio (3) kulchibo kulkulchibo lagim kobiga, 2010; MS122.002.014.00022; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo lead lunga drum language audio (4) alkali soli bilimori gnun ti zori mpahili, 2010; MS122.002.014.00023; Locke, David
    - Dambobugo answer lunga drum language audio (1) Dambobugo din tagi, 2010; MS122.002.014.00024; Locke, David
  - Jerigu, solo dance, 1999 -- 2010; MS122.002.015; 26 Digital Object(s)
    Jerigu is the appellation of Kar-naa Ziblim. When Kar-naa Ziblim's father died, there were many sons who were eligible to replace him, most of whom were older and richer than Ziblim. Though lacking in wealth and stature, Ziblim was well known for his respectful and helpful character, and so was chosen to succeed his father as Kar-naa. The drum language for Jerigu says that a foolish man uses his money to buy gold, but a wise man uses his character to buy respect.
    - Story of Jerigu N-Dari O Salima, appellation of Kar-naa Ziblim, 1999; MS122.002.015.00001; Locke, David; Lunna, Abubakari
      Told by Abubakari Lunna on March 15, 1999. Edited by David Locke. Describes the Jerigu rhythm played in honor of the chief Kar-naa Ziblim, which describes how Kar-naa Ziblim came to power.
    - Jerigu N-Dari O Salima lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.015.00002; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Jerigu N-Dari O Salima lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.015.00003; Locke, David
    - Jerigu N-Dari O Salima lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.015.00004; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Jerigu N-Dari O Salima lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.015.00005; Locke, David
    - Jerigu N-Dari O Salima lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.015.00006; Locke, David
    - Jerigu N-Dari O Salima answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.015.00007; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Jerigu N-Dari O Salima answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.015.00008; Locke, David
    - Jerigu N-Dari O Salima answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.015.00009; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Jerigu N-Dari O Salima answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.015.00010; Locke, David
    - Jerigu N-Dari O Salima answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.015.00011; Locke, David
    - Jerigu N-Dari O Salima lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.015.00012; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David